In this video, you'll learn about Sponsored Brands, a solution that helps you build your brand on
Amazon to better reach shoppers as they consider which products to purchase.
We'll explore how Sponsored Brands work and how it can help you meet your campaign objectives by
connecting you directly with shoppers looking for products similar to yours.
As a note, Sponsored Brands are available for professional sellers or vendors who have enrolled
in Amazon Brand Registry.
Sponsored Brands ads appear in placements above, alongside, and below shopping results, as well
as within product detail pages.
Sponsored Brands campaigns are designed to help increase awareness and consideration around your
brand, but also to inspire shoppers to visit your page and finally make a purchase.
Sponsored Brands ads include your brand's logo and headline alongside a collection of your products.
You have control over your ad's messaging and creatives.
Similar to Sponsored Products, Sponsored Brands use a cost-per-click model, meaning you only pay
when shoppers click your ads.
This lets you choose how much you want to bid per click and control how much you spend on campaigns
overall.
Now that you know how Sponsored Brands can help you engage shoppers, let's learn how to get started
with your first campaign.
Number one, define your campaign goal.
It's important to know what business goal you want to accomplish with advertising.
Remember, Sponsored Brands campaigns can be great at helping shoppers to discover and consider your
brand.
You may want to focus on metrics like product detail page views, impressions, or new to brand metrics
to see if your ads are helping reach new shoppers.
Number two, create a campaign.
Now that your goals are ready, sign in to your advertising console account.
Click the Create Campaign button and choose Sponsored Brands.
Number three, choose your campaign settings, choose a campaign name that's easy to identify and
remember.
Note that this campaign name is only visible to you.
Follow this by entering the start and end dates for your campaign.
Remember, it's recommended to create your campaign with no end date so it can run year round unless
you have a specific seasonal goal.
Finally, set your budget.
You have the flexibility to choose between a daily budget or lifetime budget during campaign creation.
Your budget should be high enough to keep your ads showing throughout your selected campaign duration.
Number four, select an ad format.
Sponsored Brands gives you access to three ad formats.
Ad formats are templates that help you create ads based on what you'd like to promote.
Product collection ad format lets you promote your products and offers the opportunity to create
a more rich shopping experience through the use of branded imagery.
Store Spotlight ad format lets you take advantage of your store, helping shoppers more easily discover
the different product categories available within your store.
Video ad format displays six to 45 seconds, auto-playing video in mobile and desktop shopping results.
Number five, choose your products.
Select the products that you want to advertise from the list of eligible products displayed from
your catalog.
You must feature at least three products but no more than 100.
Choose products in the same category or products with similar keywords.
Note that the campaign will automatically pause for sponsored brands if linking to a product list
page with less than two in-stock products.
Number six, set up your ad creative.
Now you can customize your ad.
Choose your brand name and create a headline to help tell a story about your brand.
You can also add custom images of your brand or products to further enhance your story.
Finally, choose the order in which you'd like your products to appear when shoppers click your ad.
Number seven, choose your targeting tactic.
Sponsored brands gives you the option to choose between keyword and product targeting.
Keyword targeting lets you choose keywords to help your product appear in shopping results.
Product targeting lets you choose categories or specific products to target your ad to.
You can also further refine product targeting by brand, price range, or review ratings.
Number eight, add negative targeting.
Depending on which targeting tactic you choose, you will have an option to add negative targeting
to your campaign.
Negative targeting prevents your ads from appearing on specific shopping results or detail pages
that don't meet your performance goals.
This in turn can refine your audience and improve your return on ad spend.
Number nine, define your bidding.
You have the flexibility to choose your cost per click bid during campaign creation and can change
it at any time.
Choose your bid based on the maximum amount you're willing to pay when a shopper clicks your ad.
Once you complete these steps, you are ready to launch your first sponsored brands campaign.
Sponsored brands' ads require approval and must be submitted for review prior to publishing.
It's important to consider how sponsored brands fits into your broader advertising strategy.
You can use sponsored brands to drive broader awareness and consideration for your brand and use
sponsored products
to reach high-intent shoppers looking to make a purchase.
Ready to get started?
Visit ads.
amazon.
com